<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hugo on bjartek - random musings of a nerd</title><link>https://bjartek.org/tags/hugo/</link><description>Recent content in hugo on bjartek - random musings of a nerd</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><managingEditor>bjarte@bjartek.org (Bjarte S. Karlsen)</managingEditor><webMaster>bjarte@bjartek.org (Bjarte S. Karlsen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 21:13:23 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bjartek.org/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blogging with BeatutifulHugo</title><link>https://bjartek.org/post/beatutifulhugo/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 21:13:23 +0200</pubDate><author>bjarte@bjartek.org (Bjarte S. Karlsen)</author><guid>https://bjartek.org/post/beatutifulhugo/</guid><description>After searching and trying out lots of different themes i settled on beautifulhugo.
The criera I have for chooing a theme can be found in blogging
Some of the other themes I tried was:
kiara eureka papermod anatole</description></item><item><title>Blogging with Puml</title><link>https://bjartek.org/post/puml/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 22:03:48 +0200</pubDate><author>bjarte@bjartek.org (Bjarte S. Karlsen)</author><guid>https://bjartek.org/post/puml/</guid><description>PlantUML is another passion of mine for making diagrams. As you might have realised I like working with things that are ascii text and not WYSIWYG.
Here is an example of a image that is generated using github actions. The PUML file resides in static in this repo and it generates a png when the site is built.</description></item><item><title>Blogging with code</title><link>https://bjartek.org/post/code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:15:23 +0200</pubDate><author>bjarte@bjartek.org (Bjarte S. Karlsen)</author><guid>https://bjartek.org/post/code/</guid><description>When writing a technical blog you often want to include code snippts inside your blog posts, however you do not want to have to do tedious copy and paste between your actual code and the blog posts. Also you want to ensure that your code actually compiles. There is nothing more annoying then code samples that does not compile.
In order to cope with this I have crated a shortcode code for hugo that allows me to</description></item><item><title>Blogging with Hugo</title><link>https://bjartek.org/post/blogging/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:13:23 +0200</pubDate><author>bjarte@bjartek.org (Bjarte S. Karlsen)</author><guid>https://bjartek.org/post/blogging/</guid><description>I decided to start up blogging again. My eyes have long been on hugo as a blogging plattform.
My needs for blogging are:
blog showing actual syntax highlight code blog using plantuml diagrams blog using markdown Hugo makes all of that possible although plantuml integration does not look to be as smooth as I want yes. More on that later.
I struggled for a long time finding a theme I like, for now I am kiera, but not sure it will stay that way.</description></item></channel></rss>